Hello and welcome to the 31st tutorial
on how to program in Gcript 2. So in
this tutorial I'm going to show you
something called trigger client and for
that I created a new weapon called
action client and added it to myself
already. So let's put client side
function on uh what do we
want on player
chats we're going to put if
player.hat.st starts. So if you're just
if what you're saying whatever you're
saying if it starts with the text
slashfind then oh two two parenthesis
then we're going to
put
temp.pame and so this is a new variable
and make it player
chat. We could replace this with any
variable actually along with here. We
could actually put this dot some text
and it'll take this text variable and
whatever it starts with. And yeah, but
we're going to put
player. And then over here we're going
to put
player.string. Now substring is going to
take out a part of the text. And we're
going to take out that part and put it
into this new
variable. So we're going to take out
five. Now, five doesn't take out the
first five letters. It's going to take
out all the letters past the letter, the
fifth letter. So, we're going to take
this, this, this, this, this. Those
aren't going to be taken. Then
everything past that is going to be
taken.
So, now we may want a space here as
well. Yeah, that'll be a good idea to
have a space. Then, we'll put a six
here.
Okay. Then, let's go here and put
player. chat is equal to temp.pame just
to test. All right. Now, if I
say hind, as you can see over here, I'm
saying
/find. Oh, with a
space. Oh, wait. So, we may want to
um edit this a bit. So, let's say we
don't want to count any of these spaces
here. Well, we could do this, but then
everything we say is not going to be
able to have a space. Well, if we go
here after substring and puttrim
um then parenthesis, this is going to
make it so that it cuts out all the um
spaces there. So, we can change this
back to five. So, even if we put
something like slashfind space la, it's
just going to take up the la include the
space. So
there now we type
slashfind and nothing. It's g not not
going to say anything because we didn't
put anything after the slashfind. Now if
we put you can kind of hard to see
but nah whatever. Now if we put
slashfind
space what do we want? Some words. It's
going to say some words. Now, if we to
if we didn't put a space there, just
slashfind some words. You can see I took
out that space. It's still going to say
some words. Reason being because we have
dot trim here, which is taking out the
spaces.
Okay. So, after this, we're going to
take out we don't want it to say
ourselves to say it anymore. We're going
to put trigger
server
gui
name, temp.pn name because we want to
send over that variable we just made.
Then here we're going to put function
onaction server
side and rename this variable we just
sent to let's just not rename it
temp.pame. Keep it the same. All right.
Now we're over on server
side. Now let's put a for loop and put
temp.pl there. And we're going to loop
through all the players on the server
using the variable
temp.pl. Then if pl which is the account
of all the players if any of them nick.
So if the nick the the account of okay
let me explain that. So we're this is
the account of all the players pretty
much. If one of those players as it's
looping through if one of those players
nick which is their nickname is equal to
the text we just said
temp.pame if it's equal to
that then we're going to
put pl which is the player that's
already at chat is equal to that's
me. Okay. So I'm saying slashfind then
some words. It's looping through
everyone on the server. If anyone's name
is equal to those words, they're going
to say
this. Okay. Now, if we type /find test,
which is the name of this test person
right here, they're going to say that's
me. If we put someone that doesn't exist
here, like let's say Bob, Bob is not on
the server, but if we put it well, no
one's going to say anything. If we put
zero g, which is me, I'm gonna say
that's
me. All right.
Now, let's use trigger
client. Okay. Trigger client is a thing
that's going to go from server side to
client side. So, it's the opposite of
trigger server. So, let's have that
here. After that person says it, we're
going to put player. It's not them, but
us. Player trigger
client.Goy because it's in a weapon,
comma, this name. Specify what weapon we
want to use this in. Then we don't want
to send any variables over.
Now, let's make it bigger. Now, over
here under client
side, we're going to put function on
action client side.
All right. Now, let's put show
image. It's 300. Then whatever image
block.png, then
player.x,
player.y. Actually, no, we're not going
to do that. We're not going to put it on
ourselves. We're going to put it on the
other person. So,
uh, let's change the image first. Let's
change the image. Something a bit more
fancy.
blue_rupy. That's something I have. You
probably don't have it. So, you can put
something else. Now, over here, I'm
going to put
uh the name of the Well, actually, I
want to send over those variables first.
Over here on player.triggerclient, we're
going to send over the
variable. Um, we're going to send over
pl.x and send
overpl.y. So, it's going to send over
this player's accounts x value and their
y-value. Then over here in the
parenthesis, we're just going to keep it
like this. plx comm,
ply. Then over here, we're going to put
plx. And over here,
ply. The x1 is going to be applied to
the plx. The y1's going to be applied to
the
ply. All right. If we try
that. Um, there he's in observer mode.
One second.
Okay, now these back. I'm going to show
you what it does. Okay, so actually I'm
going to test it. So I was going to
find test. Now he's going to say that's
me. And then this rupee is going or this
image is going to appear on his X and Y.
Now if we look at this player's account,
this player's window, you can see the
rupee is not there.
I did only I can see it the per since I
typed in slashfind and then his name.
Now that's because this is on client
side. So that's pretty useful actually.
Uh you can make things that only the
player can see after going from server
side to client side. Now, trigger client
will only work if you have first gone to
server side and you're going back to
client side, which is pretty lame, but
you know, whatever. Um, so you can only
use trigger client if you've already
used trigger server, gone server side,
you trigger client, and gone back to
client side. Well, anyway, uh, let's try
that again. We could also make the rupee
disappear after a while. So let's put
sleep
two. Then we're going to put the image
again, but just take out
this. So it's not going to be it's going
to be a blank image. All right. Now, if
I type in um slashfind test, it's going
to loop through everyone. Find the
person named test. He's going to have
the image appear next to him and the
chat. So it shows me okay that's that
guy. Now there's a lot more you can do
with church client. You can also go to
client side on other
people. So let's show how that works.
Instead of putting playerclient side
we're going to put pl.client side cuz
that's the current player that we're
looping
through.
Now we're doing client side to them on
this current weapon as well. So they
have to have this weapon as well cuz
we're putting this name. Okay, let me
explain this again. On client side, I am
going to say /find and then some words.
It's going to go to server side. It's
going to loop through everyone on the
server. Loop through everyone on the
server. And if somebody's nickname is
equal to the text I just said after
slashfind, they are going to say that's
me. And then this trigger client's going
to happen to them, not me anymore. I'm
changing that. And it's going to happen
to them on this weapon, assuming they
have it. If they don't have it, then
it's not going to work. But if they do
have it, it is going to
work. So, it's going to run this here.
It's going to run this code, line of
code, this block of code over here for
them. Not for me, but for
them. All right, let's apply that and
see how it works. I'm going to hold this
over here. This test player over here.
Actually over
here. I'll show them in a second. So,
first I'm going to say
slash find then
test. So, he's going to say that's me.
Oh, probably didn't catch that. Here.
I'll I'll do it on the other player
instead. Find zerog.
So, it's going to I'm going to say find
zero
g, which is pretty
useful. Let's type that again. Find
zero
g. Oh, wait. Why is the rupy appearing
on
me? Well, oh, yeah, that's that's cuz I
made it that way. See, the rupee appear
now appears on the opposite person, not
on myself. So I'm going to type
slashfind zero g on this test account
and only the rupee is going to appear on
me only. Now we could have other things
happen. Instead of the rupee appearing
we could have maybe an image appear that
says do you want to join this guild and
they could say yes or no and then it'll
send it'll go back to server side but do
it for me instead or something like
that. We could do a lot of things with
this. Uh you can do whatever you want on
client side here. Um, and I guess that
concludes this tutorial. Let me explain
that one more time. So here I'm going to
say slashfind. It's going to take that
variable I said after slashfind to
everyone on a server if their nickname
is equal to that variable. It's going to
go to them and make the rupee appear for
them. It's also going to make them say
this say this say that's me. But
everyone can see that because it's
chat. So that con this tutorial and I'll
see you next time. Here let me show you
one more. Let me show you the example
again. Over here on this test person,
I'm going to say
slashfind zero G. And when I say it,
it's going to say that's me. And the
rupee is going to appear on that
player's window. Not on mine, but just
on that players. That concludes his